# **Blanca Mendizabal Perello**

Full-stack software developer recently graduated from Makers Academy, Europe's leading web development bootcamp. I'm looking for a junior developer position in a company where I can make an impact and also grow professionally.

Blog I GitHub I LinkedIn I Twitter

#### **Skills**

### **Project Management**

I've shown strong ability breaking projects into smaller tasks while working atLittle Bee Community. I managed a project in Africa, creating a three-year timeline that included monthly and weekly tasks, cost tracking, and list of suppliers. This structured workflow made it easier to deliver the project on time and on budget.

#### **Adaptability**

For the last five years I have been experiencing big changes in my life, and I managed to successfully overcome them by focusing on my strengths and abilities. My last challenge, a career change, started one year ago when I began learning HTML, CSS and JavaScript by myself. I then decided to join Makers Academy, a 12-week bootcamp where I learnt Ruby, Rails, Node, and React, to name a few technologies. It has been an amazing and satisfying journey!

#### **Communication and Collaboration**

My colleagues at Makers highlight my empathy, patience, and ability to explain concepts clearly as my main skills. For example, on one specially challenging week I noticed that my colleague was struggling with understanding how a Node app works. I helped her analyse the project's structure and data flow. By the end of the day we managed to have a server up and running!

#### **Design and User Experience**

I'm passionate about crafting attractive and user-friendly interfaces for every project I work on. I have taught myself CSS, Bootstrap, Photoshop, InDesign, and Illustrator. I have used these skills to create appealing and usable apps in personal projects, and marketing materials for Little Bee Community and Battle McCarthy.

## **Projects**

Name	Description	Technologies	Timeframe
Twitch.tv streaming	JavaScript with Ajax requests	JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap	3 days
Wikipedia search	JavaScript with Ajax requests	JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap	1 day
CSS playground	Live-editing HTML and CSS tool	JavaScript, React, Jest	10 days
StoryApp	JavaScript single-page application	JavaScript, jQuery, Jasmine, HTML, CSS	5 days

## **Experience**

Sustainability Consultant at Little Bee Community (London, UK) Oct 2013 - Aug 2016

Led a wide range of projects locally and abroad, ensuring goals were met on time and on budget. Created internal databases of agricultural techniques and best practices, and funding opportunities for a wide range of projects. I supported and managed volunteers and other team members.

Agricultural Engineer at Battle McCarthy (London, UK) Jan 2013 - Oct 2013

Responsible for urban agriculture R&D. I worked with five other people, developing agricultural strategies to maximise food production inside buildings using hydroponic systems.

Environmental Engineer at Aqualogy (AGBAR group) (Madrid, Spain) Sep 2011 – Sep 2012

Responsible for conducting compliance checks for the purpose of enforcing Spanish and European laws regarding water treatment. I also designed a working methodology for the analysis of biological quality parameters of Spanish rivers.

Guest Speaker at Technical University of Madrid (Madrid, Spain) Mar 2007 - Jul 2008

Participated as a guest speaker at the IV World Congress of Agricultural Engineers, presenting my final year project *'Iberian Pig Value Chain Analysis''*.

Intern (Food Sector) at Technical University of Madrid (Madrid, Spain) 2006 - 2008

Worked at the Agricultural Economy department analysing the value chain of various food products, and at the Agri-Food Industry department carrying out quality control procedures in the bread industry.

#### **Education**

Onsite Software Development Bootcamp at Makers Academy (London, UK) Aug 2016 - Dec 2016

Highly-selective 12-week full-time program (and 4-week pre-course), emphasising:

- · Front-end development
- · Back-end development
- · Pair-programming
- Test-driven development
- · Object-oriented design
- Agile methodologies

M.Sc. Environmental Engineering and Managementat EOI Business School (Madrid, Spain) 2010 -- 2011

Master thesis "Development of an Environmental Management System under the European EMAS Regulation".

M.Sc Agricultural Engineering at Technical University of Madrid (Madrid, Spain) 2000 – 2008

My final year project, "Iberian Pig Value Chain Analysis", received an outstanding qualification.

#### Other information

- English (professional working proficiency).
- · Spanish (native).
- I love making my own bread, and photography.